{
  "reference_number": "12404",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "2050 is way too far into the future . New Zealanders need to be required to reduce their greenhouse gas emissions NOW - not in 32\n years time. Half of us will be dead by then. I have trucks sitting outside the supermarket across the road from my house with their\n\n engines going all day - the Northland regional council doesn't even have a policy on engine idling so I have no way to stop them. They\n ( industry and government ) are NOWHERE with this issue. And people ridicule me for caring. Our education needs to change from\n what the problem is to focusing on what we can do about it. Including engaging with our elected representatives to demand change\n\n and the means by which we can effect it. New Zealanders are very disengaged from the democratic process."
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "BUT ONLY IF ( when ) it is shown that we need be acting with more urgency to bring emissions down."
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - each incoming Government should have the option to review the third budget in the sequence",
      "answer_index": 14,
      "notes": "BUT ONLY IF ( when ) it is shown that we need be acting with more urgency to bring emissions down."
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "BUT ONLY IF ( when ) it is shown that we need be acting with more urgency to bring emissions down."
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "BUT ... It needs to turn acheiving the goal of being greenhouse-gas free from being a pesky nuisance into being a desirable\n\naspiration for all parties. As a remote island nation that derives much of its income from primary sector exports and international\ntourism, the people of New Zealand need to be made aware of the benefits inherent in making the change away from dependence\n\non and vulnerabilty to fossil fuels and to organic plant-based diets. Being seen to be a leader in this area will be of huge benefit to our\nexport and tourism sector and to our health, mobility , economy and the environment we live in."
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "AS SOON AS POSSIBLE"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Reduce consumption of fossil fuels : Bring in legislation to stop banks from providing loans to greenhouse gas producing activities (\ne.g. loans to purchase car(bon burner)s. Bring in legislation to protect future renewable energy proposals from being bought up and\nclosed down ( e.g. as happened in 2013 when Todd Energy bought up Crest Energy's Kaipara Tidal Power generation proposal and\n\nclosed it down) . Carry out a nationwide study to identify the most appropriate sites for generation of renewable energies. Work with\nRegional , Local Territories and their communities to implement micro-power projects . Change the funding regime for transport\n\nprojects to provide funding for the extension and electrification of ALL of New Zealand's railways and create a comprehensive high-\nspeed nationwide rail-based transport system. ( We're currently burning through $21,000,000 per day in imported fossil-fuels, so ,\n\nyes, we can afford it. Put light-rail down the centre of all our motorways. Identify and actively promote conversion to horticulture ( away\nfrom our traditional dependence on agriculture ) and promote the transition to plant-based diet. ( as per \" Lesser consumption of\nanimal products is necessary to save the world from the worst impacts of climate change, UN report says\" ) . Turners and Growers\n\nwholesalers reported that we are only producing half of current horticultural products export demand."
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Google : Cheat Neutral"
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Create a monitoring system so that New Zealanders can actually SEE where we are with progress towards achieving this goal. e.g.\ndata displays at EVERY petrol station to show how much carbon we - individually - and as a nation - are burning at that particular time."
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "See my comments above. I could go on.... I am available to speak to my submission via remote conferencing ( Skype etc ) P.S. After\n\nhitting ' Continue' I found ' You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication.' - I never saw any option given for this -\nand still can't find it.\n\n\n\n\n You have elected to withhold your personal details from publication."
    }
  ]
}
